# **ERICA SNYDER**

in linkedin.com/in/ericaleesnyder

San Diego, CA 92119

github.com/ericaleesnyder

**1** (408) 966-4467



ericaleesnyder.com

ericaleesnyder@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

I am frontend engineer (and people-person) with an architectural design and psychology background. I specialize in React & TypeScript and thrive in a collaborative environment. My professional highlights include making happy clients, building accessible websites, and nurturing effective teams.

### **EDUCATION**

Post Bacc / MS Computer Science Candidate **Full Stack Flex Bootcamp Certificate Bachelor of Architecture, Psychology Minor** 

Tufts University (In Progress starting Sept. 2024) UC San Diego Extension (December 2021) Cal Poly San Luis Obispo (June 2018)

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML	CSS	JavaScript	TypeScript	Styled Components	Node.js	React	Material UI
Gatsby	Next.js	Apollo	Storybook	Contentful	DatoCMS	Builder.io	GraphQL

### **EXPERIENCE**

San Diego, CA Webstacks, Inc.

Frontend Engineer, L2 August 2023 - Present

Frontend Engineer, L1 February 2022 - August 2023

Developed and nurtured client relationships leading to excellent perception of Webstacks with client teams. Participated in months-long retainer client engagements making substantial incremental improvements to site optimizations, SEO performance, and full page builds.

Collaborated effectively with other developers and designers throughout the software development lifecycle to produce scalable modular web components for B2B SaaS companies and health care and insurance providers.

Key achievements include:

- Led the development of a redesigned help center for a key retainer client leading to improved user experience and efficiency
- Spearheaded and executed a 6 week documentation project for a key enterprise client revolutionizing their content editing experience
  - Provided robust, detailed, easy to understand instructions for each component, module, and template available in their content management system
  - Totaled over 140 instances of documentation, including 21 templates, over 50 components, 10 guides
- Planned and executed the migration of over 40 forms from Active Campaign to HubSpot. Utilized HubSpot Forms API to create a custom form generator to control styles and functionality. Maintained functionality of third party tracking integrations (Woopra, Segment) throughout the migration.

## Anderson Brulé Architects, Inc.

San Jose, CA

**Architectural Designer** 

August 2018 - September 2021

Worked closely and collaboratively with project managers, interior designers, clients, and consultants to produce technically accurate and complete architectural drawing sets. Assisted with construction documentation production and approval of small and large scale projects.

### **VOLUNTEER/PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS**

**AIA Silicon Valley** Women In Architecture (AIA Sub Committee) Member (2018 - 2021)

Secretary (mid 2020 - 2021)

Events Chair (2019 - mid 2020)